Finding Aid for the Joseph Byrne Lockey Papers LSC.0127
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Central America
  - 11. Diplomatic Representatives to Central America (British), 1825-34
    - Extract of letter from George Dashwood to Lord Palmerston. Kirtlington Park, May 2, 1832.; 29.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/12 - 7 × 9 red margin paper). (Box 1)
    - Extract of letter from Francis Murphy to Simon Cock. 15 Doughty Street, May 3, 1832.; 30.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 12/15). (Box 1)
    - Extract from letter to Sir George Dashwood from Viscount Palmerston. Foreign Office, May 7, 1832.; 31.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/12 - 7 × 9 red margin paper). (Box 1)
    - Extract of letter to Acting Consul Hall, Guatemala, from the Foreign Office, June 21, 1832.; 32.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/12 - 7 × 9 red margin paper). (Box 1)
    - Extract of letter from Mr. William Hall, British merchant, Acting Vice Consul at Guatemala, to Mrs. Charles Dashwood, August 17, 1832.; 33.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/12 - 7 × 9 red margin paper). (Box 1)
    - Extract of letter from Viscount Palmerston to Acting Consul Hall. Foreign Office, November 5, 1832.; 34.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 12/15 - 7 × 9 red margin paper). (Box 1)
    - Extract of letter from Mr. Chatfield, Vice Consul at Guatemala, to John Backhouse. London, June 12, 1833.; 35.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/13 - 7 × 9 red margin paper). (Box 1)
    - Extract of letter from Viscount Palmerston to Acting Consul Hall, Guatemala. Foreign Office, June 28, 1833.; 36.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/13 - 7 × 9 red margin paper). (Box 1)
    - Extract of letter from Mr. Chatfield Vice Consul at Guatemala to John Bidwell. London, June 30, 1833.; 37.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/13 - 7 × 9 red margin paper). (Box 1)
    - Extract of letter from Mr. Chatfield to Lord Palmerston. London, August 26, 1833.; 38.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/13 - 7 × 9 red margin paper). (Box 1)
    - Extract of letter from Viscount Palmerston to Acting Consul Hall. Foreign Office, March 19, 1834.; 39.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/15 - 7 × 9 red margin paper). (Box 1)
    - Extract of letter from Viscount Palmerston to Mr. Chatfield Vice Consul at Guatemala. Foreign Office, March 19, 1834.; 40.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/14 - 7 × 9 red margin paper). (Box 1)
    - Extract of letter from Mr. Chatfield to Viscount Palmerston,, Guatemala., June 25, 1834; 41.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/14 - 7 × 9 red margin paper). (Box 1)
    - Extract of letter from Mr. Chatfield to Viscount Palmerston. Guatemala, July 5, 1834.; 42.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/14 - 7 × 9 red margin paper). (Box 1)
    - Extract of letter from Viscount Palmerston to Mr. Stewart. Foreign Office, September 26, 1834.; 43.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 15/15 - 7 × 9 red margin paper). (Box 1)
  - 12. Guatemala, Honduras, Salvador Squier Mission: Letters on Confederation, 1842-67
    - Savage, Henry to His Excellency, Daniel Webster. Legation of the U.S.A., Guatemala, October 15, 1842.; 1.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Guatelama, vol.1 no.8). (Box 1)
    - Savage, Henry to the Honorable Daniel Webster. Guatemala, April 25, 1843.; 2.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Guatemala, vol.1 no.10). (Box 1)
    - Savage, Henry to the Honorable James Buchanan. Guatemala, October 5, 1847.; 3.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Guatemala, vol.1-). (Box 1)
    - Savage, Henry to the Honorable William L. Marcy. Legation of the U.S.A., Guatemala, December 30, 1856.; 4.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Guatemala, vol.3, no.22). (Box 1)
    - Savage, Henry to the Honorable Lewis Cass. Legation of the U.S.A., Guatemala, September 10, 1857.; 5.; (Copy, typewritten, of Guatemala, vol.3 no.26). 1p. (Box 1)
    - Savage, Henry to the Honorable Lewis Cass. Legation of the U.S.A., Guatemala, October 2, 1857.; 6.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Guatemala, vol.3 no.27). (Box 1)
    - Clarke, Beverly L. to the Honorable Lewis Cass. Legation of the U.S.A., Guatemala, September 20, 1858.; 7.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Guatemala, vol.3). (Box 1)
    - Clarke, Beverly L. to the Honorable Lewis Cass. Legation of the United States of America, Guatemala, October 15, 1859.; 8.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Guatemala, vol.3 no.14). (Box 1)
    - Crosby, E.O. to the Honorable William H. Seward. Legation of the United States of America, Guatemala City, March 25, 1862.; 9.; 4pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Guatemala, vol.4 no.10). (Box 1)
    - Crosby, E.O. to the Honorable William H. Seward. Legation of the United States of America, Guatemala, May 6, 1862.; 10.; 7pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Guatemala, vol.4 no.12). (Box 1)
    - Crosby, E.O. to the Honorable William H. Seward. Legation of the U.S.A., Guatemala, June 6, 1862.; 11.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Guatemala, vol.4 no.13). (Box 1)
    - Crosby, E.O. to the Honorable William H. Seward. Legation of the U.S.A., Guatemala, August 6, 1862.; 12.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Guatemala, vol.4 no.16). (Box 1)
      - Aycinina, P. de to H.E.E.O. Crosby. Guatemala, August 4, 1862.; 1.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Enclosure 16, from Guatemala City, August 6, 1862). (Box 1)
    - Crosby, E.O. to the Honorable William H. Seward. Legation of the United States, Guatemala, September 4, 1862.; 13.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Guatemala, vol.4 no.19). (Box 1)
    - Crosby, E.O. to the Honorable William H. Seward. Legation of the United States, Guatemala, September 6, 1862.; 14.; 3pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Guatemala, vol.4 no.20). (Box 1)
    - Partridge, James R. to the Honorable William H. Seward. U.S. Legation in Salvador, San Salvador, December 6, 1863.; 15.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Salvador, vol.1 no.25). (Box 1)
    - Partridge, James R. to the Honorable William H. Seward. U.S. Legation in Salvador. Penama, August 4, 1864.; 16.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Salvador, vol.1 no.47). (Box 1)
    - Williams, A.S. to the Honorable William H. Seward. Legation of the United States, San Salvador, February 2, 1867.; 17.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Salvador, vol.1 no.7). (Box 1)
    - Crosby, E.O. to the Honorable William H. Seward. Legation of the United States, Guatemala, September 21, 1862.; 18.; 3pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Guatemala, vol.4 no.22). (Box 1)
      - Aycinina, P. de to E.O. Crosby. Dept. of Foreign Affairs, Guatemala, September 12, 1862.; 1.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of enclosure 1-22). (Box 1)
      - Chamarro, Fernando and Maximo Jerez. Memorandum., 2.; 3pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Enclosure 2-22). (Box 1)
      - Aycinena, P. de to Don Jose' Mariano Rodriquez. Guatemala, August 29, 1862.; 3.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Enclosure 3-22). (Box 1)
      - Milla, J. Department of State of Guatemala, September 10, 1862.; 4.; (Copy, typewritten, of Enclosure no.4-22). 2pp. (Box 1)
    - Crosby, E.O. to the Honorable William H. Seward. Legation of the United Statex, Guatemala, December 8, 1863.; 19.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Guatemala, vol.4 no.63). (Box 1)
    - Partridge, James R. to the Honorable William H. Seward. Legation of the United States in Honduras, Santa Rosa, April 28, 1862.; 20.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Honduras, vol.1 no.3). (Box 1)
    - Partridge, James R. to the Honorable W.H. Seward, Legation of the U.S. in Honduras - Comayagua, June 30, 1862.; 21.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Honduras, vol.1 no.7). (Box 1)
    - Partridge, James R. to the Honorable W.H. Seward. U.S. Legation in Honduras, La Union (Bay of Fonseca), August 6, 1862.; 22.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Honduras, vol.1 no.10). (Box 1)
    - Rousseau, R.H. to Honorable W.H. Seward. Legation of the U.S.A. at the Republic of Honduras, Tegucigalpa, September 12, 1866.; 23.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Honduras, vol.2 no.7). (Box 1)
      - Burchard, Wm.C. to Honorable R.H. Rousseau. Consulate of the U.S.A. at Comayagua and Tegucigalpa, September 11, 1866.; 1.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Enclosure 7). (Box 1)
      - Alverado, Francisco to the Comander in Chief of the Port of Omoa. Truxillo, July 11, 1866.; 2.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Enclosure no.1 to Dispatch no.7). (Box 1)
      - Espinoza, Felipe to the Minister of Finance and War of the Supreme Government of Honduras. Omoa, July 15, 1866.; 3.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten of Enclosure no.2 to Dispatch no.7). (Box 1)
    - Rousseau, R.H. to Honorable William H. Seward. Legation of the U.S.A. at the republic of Honduras. Tegucigalpa, November 16, 1866.; 24.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Honduras, vol.2 no.10). (Box 1)
    - Rousseau, R.H. to Honorable W.H. Seward. Office of U.S. legation, Tegucigalpa, Honduras, March 15, 1867.; 25.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Honduras, vol.2). (Box 1)
    - Rousseau, R.H. to His Excellency, Don Jose M. Medina. United States Legation, Tegucigalpa, March 2, 1867.; 1.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Enclosure no.1 to Dispatch from Gegucigalpa). (Box 1)
    - Medina, J.M. to Honorable R.H. Rousseau. Tegucigalpa, March 9, 1867.; 2.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Enclosure no.2 to Dispatch from Gegucigalpa). (Box 1)
  - 13. Honduras
    - Rousseau, R.H. to Honorable William H. Seward. Legation of the United States at the Republic of Honduras, Tegucigalpa, November 16, 1866.; 1.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Honduras, vol.2 no.9). (Box 1)
    - Yrisarri, A.J. to Honorable William H. Seward. Legation of Guatemala, Brooklyn, November 16, 1864.; 2.; 3pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Notes from Central American Legations, vol.5). (Box 1)
    - Hassaurek, F. to His Exc. William H. Seward. Legation of the United States, Quito, February 19, 1864.; 3.; 3pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Ecuador, vol.7 no.114). (Box 1)
    - Hassaurek, F. to His Exc. William H. Seward. Legation of the United States, Quito, July 1, 1864.; 4.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Ecuador, vol.7 no.131). (Box 1)
    - Coggershall, William T. to Honorable William H. Seward. U.S. Legation, Quito, October 18, 1866.; 5.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Ecuador, vol.8 no.9). (Box 1)
    - Salmon, David A. to Mr. Joseph B. Lockey. Washington, November 19, 1924.; 6.; 1p. typewritten. (Box 1)
    - La Patrie., 7.; 3pp. of typewritten notes in French. 8.5 × 14 paper. (Box 1)
    - La Fin De L'Expedition Mexicaine., 8.; 3pp. of typewritten notes in French. 8.5 × 14 paper. (Box 1)
    - Nouvelles Du Mexique., 9.; 2pp. of typewritten notes in French. 8.5 × 14 paper. (Box 1)
    - Voici le texte de la convention conclue entre le gouvernement de de l'empereur des Français et celui de l'empereur du Mexique., 10.; 3pp. typewritten, notes in French. 8.5 × 14 paper). (Box 1)
    - Note, in Spanish., 11.; Typewritten, 1p. (Box 1)
    - Notes., 12.; Pen, 11pp. 8.5 × 14 ruled paper. (Box 1)
    - Notes, from the Bureau of Indexes and Archives., 13.; 2pp., typewritten. (Box 1)
    - Salmon, David A. to Professor Joseph B. Lockey. Washington, May 13, 1925.; 14.; 1p. typewritten. (Box 1)
    - Salmon, David A. to Mr. Joseph B. Lockey. Washington, October 28, 1924.; 15.; 2pp. typewritten. (Box 1)
    - Riddle, J.W. to Professor Joseph B. Lockey. Buenos Aires, May 6, 1925.; 16.; 1p. typewritten. (Box 1)
    - Riddle, J.W. to Professor Joseph B. Lockey. Buenos Aires, May 8, 1925.; 17.; 1p. typewritten. (Box 1)
    - Morgan, Edwin V. to Mr. Joseph B. Lockey. Rio de Janeiro, May 30, 1925.; 18.; 1p. typewritten. (Box 1)
    - [Unknown] to Joseph B. Lockey, M.A., Ph.D., Washington, August 14, 1924.; 19.; 1p. typewritten. (Box 1)
    - Salmon, David A. to Mr. Joseph B. Lockey. Washington, October 16, 1924.; 20.; 1p. typewritten. (Box 1)
    - Salmon, David A. to Mr. Joseph B. Lockey. Washington, April 24, 1925.; 21.; 3pp. typewritten. (Box 1)
    - Note, Joseph B. Lockey., 22.; 1p. typewritten. (Box 1)
    - Salmon, David A. to Professor John B. Lockey. Washington, January 8, 1925.; 23.; 2pp. typewritten. (Box 1)
    - Lockey, Joseph B. to David A. Salmon, May 7, 1925.; 24.; Carbon. 1p. typewritten. (Box 1)
    - Fenstermacher, Harvey E. to Mr. Joseph B. Lockey. Washington, D.C., December 6, 1924.; 25.; 1p. Pen. (Box 1)
    - Fleiuss, Dr. Max to Señor Dr. Joseph B. Lockey. Rio de Janeiro, August 10, 1925.; 26.; 1p. typewritten. (Box 1)
      - Enclosure to letter above., 1.; 1p. typewritten. (Box 1)
      - Envelope, addressed in typewriting. Instituto Historico e Geographico Brasileiro to Dr. Joseph Lockey. Date unreadable., 2. (Box 1)
    - Envelope, addressed in typewriting. American Embassy, Rio De Janeiro, Brazil to Mr. Joseph B. Lockey, May 31, 1925.; 27. (Box 1)
    - Crosby, E.O. to Honorable William H. Seward. Legation of the United States, Guatemala, March 22, 1864.; 28.; 2pp. typewritten (Copy of Dispatches from Guatemala, vol.4 no.68). (Box 1)
      - Enclosure 68 above. Gutierres, Carlos to H.E. the Honorable Earl Russel. Legation of the Republic of Salvador to H.B.M., London, July 1863.; 1.; 4pp. Copy translation. (Box 1)
    - Crosby, E.O. to Honorable William H. Seward. Legation of the United States, Guatemala, May 7, 1864.; 29.; 4pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Guatemala, vol.4 no.71). (Box 1)
    - Warren, Fitz to The Secretary of State. City of Guatemala, July 13, 1867.; 30.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Guatemala, vol.5 no.22). (Box 1)
    - Riotte, C.N. to Honorable William H. Seward. Legation of the U.S.A., Costa Rica. San Jose, October 13, 1863.; 31.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Costa Rica, vol.2 no.86). (Box 1)
    - Riotte, C.N. to Honorable William H. Seward. Legation of the U.S.A., Costa Rica. San Jose, December 20, 1863.; 32.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Costa Rica, vol.2 no.90). (Box 1)
      - Enclosure no.5-90. Extract from Register Miscellan. Correspond., 1.; 2pp. typewritten. (Box 1)
    - Riotte, C.N. to Honorable William H. Seward. Legation of the U.S.A., Costa Rica, San Jose, January 14, 1864.; 33.; 3pp. typewritten (Copy of Dispatches from Costa Rica, vol.2 no.93). (Box 1)
      - Enclosure no.1 to Dispatch no.93. Extract from Register Miscell. Correspond., 1.; 1p. typewritten. (Box 1)
    - Riotte, C.N. to Honorable William H. Seward. Legation of the U.S.A., Costa Rica, San Jose, September 23, 1865.; 34.; 3pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Costa Rica, vol.2 no.132). (Box 1)
    - Nelson, Thomas H. to Honorable William H. Seward. Legation of the United States, Santiago de Chile, July 30, 1864.; 35.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Chile, vol.21 no.144). (Box 1)
    - Nelson, Thomas H. to Honorable William H. Seward. Legation of the United States, Santiago de Chile, June 16, 1864.; 36.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Chile, vol.21 no.134). (Box 1)
    - Burton, Allan A. to Honorable William H. Seward. Legation of the United States, Bogata, June 6, 1866.; 37.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Columbia, vol.23 no.242). (Box 1)
    - Sullivan, Peter J. to Honorable William H. Seward. Legation of the United States, Bogata, August 10, 1867.; 38.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Columbia, vol.26 no.12). (Box 1)
      - Enclosure 12 - Dispatches from Columbia, vol.26 no.12. Grana, March 17, 1864.; 1.; 2pp. typewritten. (Box 1)
    - Dickinson, A.B. to Honorable William H. Seward. Legation of the United States to Nicaragua, Granada, March 18, 1864.; 39.; 1p. Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Nicaragua, vol.9 no.60). (Box 1)
    - Partridge, James R. to Honorable William H. Seward. U.S. Legation in Salvador, Guatemala, January 30, 1865.; 40.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Salvador, vol.1 no.54). (Box 1)
      - Partridge, James R. to Honorable W.H. Seward. U.S. Legation in Salvador, San Salvador, March 29, 1865.; 41.; 4pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Salvador, vol.1 no.63). (Box 1)
      - Williams, A.S. to Honorable William H. Seward. United States Legation, San Salvador, September 22, 1867.; 42.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Salvador, vol.1 no.29). (Box 1)
  - 14. Interoceanic Railroad
    - Prospectus of the Honduras Interoceanic Railway Company, Limited, March 26, 1857.; 1.; (Copy, photostat, of Foreign Office 39/7 - 11.75 × 15.5 paper). 3pp. (Box 1)
    - Honduras Interoceanic Railway Company Limited., 2.; 3pp. (Copy, photostat, of Foreign Office 39/2 - 11.75 × 15.5 paper). (Box 1)
  - 15. Manuscripts -- Central America
    - Manuscript, The Scene of Conflict., 1.; Typewritten, 13pp. (Box 1)
    - Manuscript, copy of Manuscript above., 2.; Pen, 20pp. (Box 1)
  - 16. Miscellaneous
    - Urruela, Manuel Ortiz. Report on England, United States, and Central America. Paris, January 14, 1856.; 1.; (Copy, photostat, of Foreign Office 15/89.) 12pp. (Box 2)
    - Manning to Christie. Leon, Extract., May 14, 1849.; 2.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 53/19 - 7 × 9 red margin paper). (Box 2)
    - Grey, Sir C. to Lord Grey. Extract, January 14, 1852.; 3.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 5/544 - 7 × 9 red margin paper). (Box 2)
    - Grey, Charles Edward to James Green. Kings House, Jamaica, September 4, 1850.; 4.; 7pp. (Copy, photostat, of Foreign Office 53/23). (Box 2)
    - Habeus, J.W. [?] to Honorable W.L. Marcy, Secretary of State. San Juan de Nicaragua, September 6, 1855.; 5.; 3pp. (Copy, photostat.) (L.C. - Marcy Papers). (Box 2)
    - Van Buren, M. to [Unknown]. Lindenwald, March 21, 1856.; 6.; 4pp. Photostatic copy (L.C. - Marcy papers). (Box 2)
    - Hurry, Joseff [?] to [Unknown]. Smithson Institution, October 3, 1850.; 7.; 4pp. photostatic copy (L.C. - Squier Papers). (Box 2)
    - Gomez, Fg. to [Unknown]. Guatemala, August 19, 1853.; 8.; 2pp. photostatic copy (L.C. - Squier Papers). (Box 2)
    - Smyth, P. to E.G. Squier. New York, January 25, 1851.; 9.; 3pp. photostat (L.C. - Squier Papers). (Box 2)
    - Shute, C.A. [?] to E. George Squier. Washington, February 22, 1851.; 10.; 2pp. photostat (L.C. - Squier Papers). (Box 2)
    - No name, April 1, 1851.; 11.; 4pp. photostat. (L.C. - Squier Papers). (Box 2)
    - Marcy, R.B. to E. George Squier. Fort Belknap, Texas, September 24, 1854.; 12.; 1p. photostat - 7 × 9 paper.) (L.C. - Squier Papers). (Box 2)
    - Morales, Agustin to E. George Squier. San Salvador, July 30, 1851.; 13.; 3pp. photostatic copy (L.C. - Squier Papers). (Box 2)
    - Bannas, N [?] to E. George Squier. Leon, December 6, 1850.; 14.; 7pp. photostatic copy (L.C. - Squier Papers). (Box 2)
    - Scott, Winfield to J.M. Clayton. Washington, March 4, 1852.; 15.; 6pp. photostatic copy (L.C. - Squier Papers). (Box 2)
    - [Unreadable], Pablo to E. George Squier. Leon de Nicaragua, August 12, 1850.; 16.; 4pp. photostatic copy (L.C. - Squier Papers). (Box 2)
    - [Unreadable], Pablo to E. George Squier, or place visible.)., (n.d.; 17.; 1p. photostatic copy (L.C. - Squier Papers). (Box 2)
    - Yulee, D.L. [?] to E. George Squier. Washington, D.C, December 20, 1856.; 18.; 3pp. photostatic copy (L.C. - Squier Papers). (Box 2)
    - Barlown, R.L. [?] to E.G. Squier. New York, October 21, 1851.; 19.; 4pp. photostat (L.C. - Squier Papers). (Box 2)
  - 17. Mosquito Indians, Treaty of with, 1843
    - El Tratado, con los Indios Moscos., 1843; 1.; Booklet. Blue cover. 36pp. printed. 10.5 × 7 paper. (Box 2)
  - 18. Mosquito King
    - Frederick, George [?] to [Unknown]. Bluefields, August 30, 1848.; 1.; 2pp. photostatic copy (Foreign Office 53/11). (Box 2)
    - [A(?)] to Mr. Merivale. Memo, April 16, 1850.; 2.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Foreign Office 53/25 no.22 - 7 × 9 red margin paper). (Box 2)
    - Observer & Gazette., 3.; 2pp. Photostatic copy of a newspaper (Foreign Office - 53. 12 × 16 paper). (Box 2)
  - 19. Newspaper
    - Providence Journal, Saturday Morning, February 2, 1861.; 1.; 2pp. Photostatic copy - 11.5 × 14 paper. (Box 2)
    - Extract from New York Herald, August 3, 1849.; 2.; 1p. (Copy, photostat, of Foreign Office 5/500). (Box 2)
    - Extract from New York Herald, August 5, 1849.; 3.; 1p. (Copy, photostat, of Foreign Office 5/500). (Box 2)
    - Extract from New York Herald, August 2, 1849.; 4.; 1p. (Copy, photostat, of Foreign Office 5/500). (Box 2)
    - National Intelligencer, Washington, Friday, October 12 1849.; 5.; 2pp. (Copy, photostat, of Foreign Office 5/501). (Box 2)
    - Estados de Centro-America. Pronunciamiento del Ejercito Nacional., 6.; 1p. (Copy, photostat, of Foreign Office 15/61). (Box 2)
    - Correo de Nicaragua., 7.; 2pp. (Copy, photostat, of Foreign Office 53/26 - 19 × 11.5 paper). (Box 2)
    - Nicaragua Flag, July 26, 1851.; 8.; 4pp. (Copy, photostat, of Foreign Office 15/71). (Box 2)
    - No Name., 9.; 3pp. (Copy, photostat, of Foreign Office 15/95 - 11.5 × 19 paper). (Box 2)
    - From The Leader of Interoceanic Communication, The Junction of the Atlantic and Pacific Ocean., July 31, 1858.; 10.; 2pp. Photostatic copy of Foreign Office 39/5. (Box 2)
    - Gaceta de Guatemala, December 21, 1856.; 11.; 2pp. Photostatic copy. (Box 2)
    - Squier, E.G. Letters to the Editor of the New York Herald and To the Public (Foreign Office 5/647[?])., 12.; 1p. photostatic copy. (Box 2)
    - The Great Southern Confederacy. No name. (Washington, November 19 written in along margin)., 13.; 1p. photostatic copy. (Box 2)
  - 20. Nicaragua (Dispatches)--Privateer in William Walker--Filibustering to, 1866
    - Wheeler, Jno. H. to Honorable William L. Marcy. Legation of the United States of America, Granada, September 21, 1855.; 1.; 1p. Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Nicaragua, vol.2 no.23). (Box 2)
    - Wheeler, John H. to Honorable William L. Marcy. Legation of the United States, Granada, October 14, 1855.; 2.; 1p. Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Nicaragua, vol.2 no.25). (Box 2)
      - Walker, William. Manifesto addressed to Nicaraguans. Granada, October 13, 1855.; 1.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of Enclosure 25 - October 14, 1855 from Granada, Nicaragua). (Box 2)
    - Wheeler, Jno. H. to Honorable William L. Marcy. Legation of the United Stated, Granada, October 23, 1855.; 3.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Nicaragua, vol.2 no.26). (Box 2)
      - Wheeler, Jno. H. to General Ponciano Corral. Legation of the U.S.A., Virgin Bay, October 18, 1855.; 1.; 2pp. (Copy, typewritten, of enclosure A-26 - October 23, 1855 from Granada, Nicaragua). (Box 2)
      - Corral, Ponciano to the Minister of the U.S.A. in Nicaragua. Headquarters, marching, October 17, 1855.; 2.; 1p. (Copy, typewritten, of enclosure B-26 - October 23, 1855 from Granada, Nic'a). (Box 2)
    - Wheeler, Jno. H. to Honorable William L. Marcy. Legation of the U.S.A., Granada, October 30, 1855.; 4.; 2pp. Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Nicaragua, vol.2 no.27). (Box 2)
      - Walker, Wm., and Ponciano Corral. Treaty of Peace, October 30, 1855.; 1.; 4pp. (Copy, typewritten, of Enclosure 27, from Granada, Nicaragua). (Box 2)
    - Wheeler, Jno. H. to Honorable William L. Marcy. Legation of the U.S.A., Granada, December 15, 1855.; 5.; 4pp. Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Nicaragua, vol.2 no.32). (Box 2)
    - Wheeler, Jno. H. to Honorable William L. Marcy. Legation of the U.S.A., Granada, January 25, 1855.; 6.; 1p. Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Nicaragua, vol.2 no.40). (Box 2)
    - Wheeler, Jno. H. to Honorable William L. Marcy. Legation of the U.S.A., Granada, May 15, 1856.; 7.; 2pp. Copy, typewritten, of Dispatches from Nicaragua, vol.2 no.51). (Box 2)